Andy Stanier MChem MSc

andy.stanier@gmail.com www.andystanier.co.uk LinkedIn

Northwich, Cheshire

Andy Stanier has over 6 years' experience as a software developer after having completed a master's degree in computer science with distinction. With a background in chemistry and 15 years' experience in the pharmaceutical industry, Andy is now a proficient and motivated developer using .NET framework software.

Having being made redundant from the pharmaceutical industry several times, Andy decided to pursue his long-held interest in computer programming. Having undertaken several different online courses in programming and computer science as well as using books and YouTube videos to learn new skills, he enrolled in a computer science master's degree at the University of Hertfordshire, thus enabling him to gain a recognised formal qualification.

Once he had graduated, Andy found a job as a web developer using C#, JavaScript and T-SQL and is now a full stack software developer.

Skills

Andy learned various different languages, techniques and software packages whilst studying for his master's degree. He has learned in much more depth however, over the last two years whilst working as a developer. These include C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, T-SQL, and React.

Programming Languages			Techniques/Software
C#	ASP.NET MVC and Webforms	T-SQL	MS Visual Studio 2013 - 2017
Git	TypeScript	JQuery	MS SQL Server Management Studio
HTML	CSS	PowerShell	Visual Studio Code
XML	AJAX	JSON	JIRA

Andy has also gained many transferable skills during 15 years working in the pharmaceutical industry:

- Problem Solving overcoming day-to-day issues.
- Research Skills consulting various websites and documents for ideas and solutions.
- Planning what is the best approach to deliver a solution in the shortest time.
- Tenacity working to implement the latest changes to the specification.
- Working to deadlines completing development jobs to a release window.

- Teamwork working in project teams of between 4 and 14 people.
- Independence working unaccompanied on sub-projects.

Work History

Oct 2016 - Present

Software Developer at Synectics Solutions, Stoke-On-Trent

Software developer for internal and client facing websites. Using ASP.NET MVC framework combined with C#, T-SQL, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Razor, HTML, and CSS to maintain websites for clients including the Cabinet Office, the Ministry of Defence and the automotive industry. Conversion of webforms pages to MVC. Maintenance of older code and development of new features. Use of JIRA to track and record progress. GIT and SVN for source control. Writing of Unit tests. Writing of stored procedures and queries in SQL to help with day-to-day development tasks.

Aug 2015 - Sept 2016

Distance Learning Master's Student in Computer Science, University of Hertfordshire

See Education section for more details.

May 2014 - Aug 2015

Synthetic Chemist at Molplex Pharmaceuticals, Alderley Park

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the chemistry department. Molplex was a small biochemical start-up, whose aim was to use Artificial Intelligence to design new drugs for orphan diseases.

Dec 2013 - May 2014

Looking for work - Job searching, CV writing and IT courses.

During this period, Andy attended Jobcentre run courses in CV writing, went to IT courses and applied for jobs in the pharmaceutical industry.

Jan 2011 - Dec 2013

Synthetic Organic Chemist for CK Science at Eisai, Hatfield

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the chemistry department. Designed and synthesised libraries of compounds for screening. Prepared and delivered presentations to communicate progress and problems to colleagues at project and departmental meetings.

Aug 2008 - Jan 2011

Medicinal Chemist at AstraZeneca, Charnwood, Loughborough

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the chemistry department. Designed and synthesised novel compounds within for biological screening against respiratory targets.

July 2001 - Aug 2008

Synthetic Chemist at AstraZeneca, Alderley Park, Macclesfield

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the research area. Worked within project teams to deliver compounds for biological screening in early and late stage discovery.

Education

Computer Science at University of Hertfordshire, UK

A distance learning Master's degree in Computer Science, studying the following:

- **Programming and Program Design** Learning **Java** language and Object Oriented Programming techniques using the **BlueJ** IDE. Assessment by exams and coursework; the final piece was a program, written from scratch, to a provided specification.
- **Web Scripting and Application Development** Learning about server-side website design using **ASP.NET**, **C#** and **SQL**. Created a website of user generated content.
- **Contemporary Practices in Information Technology** The ethics of information technology, assessed by researching and writing essays.
- Mobile Standards, Interfaces and Applications Learning about Ubiquitous computing, HCI, Wearable Computing, Context Awareness and using JavaScript, JSON and jQuery Mobile to generate a mobile website.
- **Secure Systems Programming** Exploring security problems with the **C** programming language and how to avoid them, plus learning about DDOS, BotNets, Worms and Viruses.
- **Software Development Tools and Methods** Ways to develop software, **UML**, **XML**, secure systems development. Assessment by essay and coursework drawing UML diagrams.
- Final Project in Computer Science A piece of research and practical work about Electronic Voting Systems, creating a desktop Java application and an HTML5 website for vote verification. Version control was handled by Git software.

As well as these taught languages and skills, C++, TypeScript, Node.js, Angular.js and AJAX were investigated during private study.

Chemistry at University of York, UK

Chemistry with a Year in Industry, MChem with First Class Honours.

Three years of study and practical labs, coursework and exams. A fourth year was spent working in an industrial setting as a synthetic chemist in a drug discovery research department. Learning on the job and completing a written report and exams.

A Levels at Tytherington High School, Macclesfield

Four 'A' Levels in Mathematics (A), Chemistry (A), Physics (B) and General Studies (A).

Projects

Most of the projects here were produced as part of my Master's course and demonstrate some of the breadth of subjects studied.

- Oscars Mobile Website This is a website written as a piece of coursework for a mobile applications course which demonstrates the use of JQuery mobile. It contains a summary of all the films that have won 'Best Picture' Oscar since the first Academy Awards in 1928 to present day, and allows users to tick them off when they have seen them.
- <u>Music Player</u> This was a website written to practice using jQuery mobile in a simple website. This project is partially complete; however, it demonstrates the use of jQuery mobile page structure and functions.
- <u>EVote</u> This was developed as part of the final project. It is a desktop Java application which simulates the creation and running of an election with electronic voting. The desktop program connects to an SQL database to collate votes.
- <u>Yahtzee Simulation</u> A Python 3 program written to simulate the rolling of 5 dice simultaneously until five-of-a-kind is rolled, the process is repeated many times and the maximum, minimum and average number of rolls needed is recorded.

This CV is also available at www.andystanier.co.uk, where links to these projects can be found.